TERRY FREIKU

HEAD CHEF

C.V

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A bright, talented and self-motivated chef with a successful track records of impressing customers with delicious meal and creative decoration food displays. Able to expertly instruct cooks and other kitchen workers in the preparation, cooking, garnishing and presentation of food to the highest standards. Experienced in the planning, directing and supervising of food preparation and cooking activities in a busy environment, having serve the past and present PRESIDENT OF GHANA AND MINISTERS.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

HEAD CHEF AT HILL CREST HOTEL -2005 TO 2008

SOUE CHEF AT A.T.S COMPANY -2008 TO 2010

ASSISTANCE HEAD CHEF AT GSS - 2012 TO 2014

HEAD CHEF AT GSS - 2014 TILL DATE

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Responsible got creating a good working atmosphere, co ordinate and motivate the kitchen staff. Making sure all procedures involved in the kitchen are in accordance with Health and Safety standards.

Duties:

Responsible for the operational management of the kitchen

Making sure that all health and safety requirement are met.

In charge of the cooking, preparation and serving of meal and refreshment

Keeping the kitchen organized, ensuring utensils are placed in the right place.

Advising new cooking techniques and equipment to kitchen staff.

Carry out the preparatory work for creating dishes

Cooking, breakfast, lunch and evening meals.

Ensure all the food produce is of the very highest standard and delicious.

Serving classic English, French and modern European cuisine.

Responding for food stock control, ordering high quality vegetable and meat.

Introducing & developing new dishes & measuring consistency and performance

Meal preparation and menu planning.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Able to cook a variety of different dishes including English and Foreign dishes.

Awareness of all health and hygiene requirements.

Experience of restaurant /pup/inn style food production

A good track records of achieving and consistently maintaining target Gross profit percentages.

Ability to work for longer hours and taking up challenges

Very good communication and writing skills

Basic computer training

Has a very good track record on food costing

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

2001-Basic School Certificate

2004-Secondary School certificate

2007-Vocational School certificate / Catering School

2007-Achieving Service Certificate

2011-Certificate for First Aid Training

AREAS OF EXPERTISE
Food preparation
Planning menus
Cost control
Kitchen hygiene
Catering
Hospitality
Food for special occasions / event
PERSONAL SKILLS
Commercially minded
Ability to delegate

REFEREES

Creative flair

SAMUEL AMOAH

A.T.S. GROUP OF COMPANY

O244031521

KWESI NSIAH

MANAGER HILLCREST HOTEL